Finding aid to the Office of the President Thomas Corwin Mendenhall Files. CA.MS.00032
Smith College Archives
- Series V. ADMINISTRATIVE OFFICES, 7.083 linear feet (18 containers)
  - Dean of Students, 1959-1972 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Dean of Students Assistant to Class Deans, 1969-1975 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Development [and Public Relations] (Box 3, Folder 9)
    see also Series VI. Alumnae - Alumnae Association - Alumnae Fund
    - Annual Reports, 1960-1974 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - General, 1959-1962 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - General, 1963-1967 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - General, 1968-1970 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - General, 1971-1975; undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Achilles Chair Endowment, 1969-1974 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Bay State Banner, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Foundations General, 1960-1971 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - George F.] Baker Trust, 1967-1974 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Braitmayer Foundation, 1965-1968 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Braitmayer Foundation, 1969-1975; undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - Brown Foundation, 1969-1974 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - Carnegie Corporation, 1960-1974 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - [Edna McConnell] Clark Foundation, 1964-1967 (Box 4, Folder 10)
        See also Series VII. Buildings & Grounds - Clark Science Center
      - [Edna McConnell] Clark Foundation, 1968-1970 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - [Edna McConnell] Clark Foundation, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - [Edna McConnell] Clark Foundation, 1972-1975; undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - Danforth Foundation, 1959-1975 (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - Dreyfus Foundation (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Dupont Committee on Educational Aid, 1963-1975 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - Educational Foundation of America, 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Esso Education Foundation, 1964-1975 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Ford Foundation
        - General, 1961-1969 (Box 5, Folder 5)
        - General, 1970-1975; undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
        - 1962 Report, DEC 1962 (Box 5, Folder 7)
        - 1962 Report Annotated, DEC 1962 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - [Ada Howe] Kent Foundation, 1970-1974 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - Kresge Foundation, 1960-1975 (Box 6, Folder 10)
      - [Henry] Luce Foundation, 1971-1973 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      - Lilly Endowment, 1973-1975 (Box 6, Folder 12)
      - Mellon Foundation, 1969-1975 (Box 6, Folder 13)
      - Merck Company, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - Merrill Trust, 1962-1975 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Mott Foundation, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - National Science Foundation, 1959-1975 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Olin Foundation, 1963-1974 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Research Corporation, 1964; 1969 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Rockefeller Foundation, 1959-1974 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Shell Companies Foundation, 1963-1967 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - Shell Companies Foundation, 1968-1974 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - [Alfred P.] Sloan, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - [Alfred P.] Sloan, 1967-1968 (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - [Alfred P.] Sloan, 1969-1975 (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - Surdna Foundation, 1969-1975 (Box 7, Folder 12)
      - Western Electric Fund, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Electronics Department, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Financial Aid
    see also Series IX. Committees & Boards - Financial Aid, Cttee on
    - General, 1959-1971 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - General, 1972-1975 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Alumnae/Smith Club Scholarships, 1963-1975 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Association of American Wives in Europe, 1964-1965 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - College Entrance Examination Board, 1965-1975 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      see also Series XV. Non-Smith Organizations College - Entrance Examination Board
    - Massachusetts Government Aid, 1967-1975 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Minority Students, 1968-1972 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Scholarships - Faculty Scholarships, 1968-1969 (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - General Motors, 1960-1971 (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - National Merit Scholarships, 1961-1964 (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - Northampton-Hatfield Scholarships, 1959-1975 (Box 9, Folder 12)
      - Proctor and Gamble, 1959-1968 (Box 9, Folder 13)
      - Scott Paper Co. Foundation, 1961-1975 (Box 9, Folder 14)
      - Miscellaneous, 1959-1974 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Student Employment/Work Study, 1960-1974 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - U.S. Department of Health, Education and Welfare, 1964-1973 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - U.S. Department of Health, Education and Welfare National - Defense Education Act, 1959-1964 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - U.S. Department of Health, Education and Welfare National - Defense Education Act Affidavit Faculty Response, 1958-1962; undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Food Services
    See Series V. Admin. Offices - Residence and Dining Services
  - Health Services, Spring 1971
    see also Series XVII. Students - Pubs - Sophian
    - Annual Reports, 1960-1966 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Annual Reports, 1967-1970 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Annual Reports, 1971-1974 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - General, 1959-1963 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - General, 1964-1966 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - General, 1967-1969 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - General, 1970-1971 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - General, 1972-1973 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - General, 1974-1975; undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - By-laws, 1961-1975 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Christian Science, 1961-1969 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Consulting and Courtesy Staff, 1959-1975 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Drugs and Alcohol, 1967-1968 (Box 11, Folder 8)
      see also Series XVII. Students - Drugs - and - Series XVII. Students - Alcohol
    - Environmental Health, 1965-1974 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Environmental Health Annual Reports, 1968-1974 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Farnsworth Study on Health Services, 1972-1973 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Gynecological Services, 1970-1973 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Smoking, 1963-1968 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Human Resources
    See Series IV. Administrative Offices - Personnel Services
  - Jahnige Social Science Research Center, 1959-1974 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Language Laboratory, 1959-1974 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Laundry, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Libraries Annual Reports, 1960-1965 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Annual Reports, 1966-1968 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Annual Reports, 1969-1972 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Annual Reports, 1973-1974 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - General, 1961-1975 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - General 1969 Survey (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - General Library Review Committee, 1973-1974 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - College Archives and Sophia Smith Collection
      - General, 1959-1968 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - General, 1969-1970 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - General, 1971-1972 (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - General, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - General, 1974-1975 (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - Julia Child Papers, 1969-1970 (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - Sylvia Plath Papers, 1966-1967; 1970-1974 (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - Margaret Sanger Papers, 1965-1974 (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - Margaret Sanger Nobel Prize, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 9)
      - Dorothy Wrinch Papers, 1971-1974 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Friends of the Smith College Library, 1959-1975 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Hillyer Art Library, 1959-1974 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Josten Performing Arts Library, 1968-1974 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Neilson Library - General, 1961-1970 (Box 13, Folder 14)
      see also Series VII. Buildings & Grounds - Neilson Library
    - Neilson Library General, 1971-1975 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Young Science Library, 1967-1973 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Museum of Art - Annual Reports
    - Annual Reports, 1960-1964 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Annual Reports, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Annual Reports, 1966-1967 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Annual Reports, 1968-1969 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Annual Reports, 1970-1971 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Annual Reports, 1972-1973 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Annual Reports, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - General, 1959-1962 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - General, 1963-1967 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - General, 1968-1969 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - General, 1970-1971 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - General, 1972-1973 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - General, 1974-1975 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - News Office, 1959-1975 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Personnel Services - Annual Reports, 1960-1966 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Annual Reports, 1967-1970 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - General, 1959-1966 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - General, 1967-1968 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - General, 1969-1973 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - General, 1974-1975 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Affirmative Action, 1968-1975 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Equal Opportunity Employment, 1970-1973 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Physical Plant
    See Series VII. Buildings and Grounds - General
  - Public Relations
  - Purchasing Office
    See Series V. Administrative Offices - Business Manager
  - Registrar, 1960-1975 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Rental Properties Annual Reports
    - Annual Reports, 1960-1964 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Annual Reports, 1965-1968 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Annual Reports, 1969-1974 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - General, 1962-1975 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Residence and Dining Services
    - Annual Reports, 1959-1965 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Annual Reports, 1966-1974 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - General, 1961-1969 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - General, 1970-1971 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - General, 1972-1974 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Cooking Staff, 1961-1971 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Dober, Paddock, Upton and Associates Study, 1968-1969 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Flambert and Flambert Food Service Study, 1963-1964 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Flambert and Flambert Food Service Study, 1965-1966 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Heads of House/Head Residents, 1962-1972 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Kosher Meals, 1969-1975 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Vassar Feeding Facilities Study, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Secretary of the College, 1965-1969 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Secretary of the College, 1970-1974 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Security, 1967-1975 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Social Science Research Center
    See Series V. Admin Offices - Janhige Social Science Resarch Center
  - Special Programs - General ee also Series IX. Committees & Boards - Social Responsibility, Committee on, 1969-1974 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Special Programs - Bridge Program, 1969-1974 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Intermediate School 201 (I.S. 201), 1968-1969 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Intermediate School 201 (I.S. 201), 1970 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Intermediate School 201 (I.S. 201), 1971 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Intermediate School 201 (I.S. 201), 1972-1975 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Smith-Amherst Tutorial, 1963-1969 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Smith-Amherst Tutorial, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Smith-Amherst Tutorial, 1971-1972 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Student Counseling Services
    See Series V Admin. Offices - Health Services - General
  - Treasurer - Annual Reports, 1960-1975 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - General, 1961-1975 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Seven Year Forecast, 1970-1974 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Ten Year Comparisons, 1961-1971 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Tuition, 1960-1975 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Twenty Year Review, 1973; 1975 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Vocational Office Annual Reports, 1960-1964 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Annual Reports, 1965-1966 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Annual Reports, 1967-1968 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Annual Reports, 1969-1970 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Annual Reports, 1971-1972 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Annual Reports, 1973-1974 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - General, 1959-1963 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - General, 1964-1971 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - General, 1972-1975 (Box 18, Folder 8)
- Series VI. ALUMNAE, 0.833 linear feet (2 containers)
  This series includes material on a number of issues related to the alumnae in general as well as the Alumnae Association and its activities. There is a series of chronological files containing letters to President Mendenhall from individual alumna. Many are routine and pro forma letters of thank you for attending certain functions, or congratulations on his successes as an administrator. However, there are also letters scattered throughout addressing specific issues of both local and national concern. Several letters from roughly 1959-1961 address Mendenhall's inauguration, the National Defense Education Act and its loyalty oath, and continuing education for adults. Many letters from 1964-1966 discuss early marriage, coeducation, minority recruitment, and campus unrest. From approximately 1969-1972 there are many letters addressing the Vietnam War and student protest. There are also letters about civil rights, coeducation, parietal regulations, equal opportunity for female academics, pass/fail grading, and the burgeoning women's liberation movement. There is additional information about continuing education for alumnae in the Graduate Work series. There is also a collection of alumnae correspondence relating to parietal regulations in the Students series.
  - Alumnae Association -General, 1959-1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - General, 1966-1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - General, 1972-1975; undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Alumnae Council Meetings, 1960-1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Alumnae Fund, 1960-1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Alumnae Fund, 1972-1975; undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Alumnae FundSophia Smith Associates, 1970-1973 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Cleveland Smith Club Lecture Series, 1960-1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Faculty Speaking Tours, 1965-1975 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Smith Alumnae Quarterly, 1967-1974 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1965-1967 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1973-1975 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Former Juniors in France, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Individuals Churchill, Ruth, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Clark, Edna VanAllen
      see Series V. Admin Offices - Development - Foundations[Edna McConnell] Clark Foundation
    - Hover, Edith Hopkins, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Kerr, Mina, 1965-1969 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Reagan, Nancy, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Snowe, Florence, 1965-1975 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Minority Alumnae, 1962-1975; undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Reunions, 1959-1975 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Series VII. BUILDINGS & GROUNDS, 2.5 linear feet (6 containers)
  This series includes records related to the maintenance and development of campus structures and infrastructure. Student Residences are grouped together and organized alphabetically. A large portion of the series consists of the records regarding the construction of the Mendenhall Center for the Performing Arts, the Clark Science Center, and the Fine Arts Center. Related material may be found in the Committees & Boards series in the records of the Space Committee and the Faculty Office Committee.
  - Annual Reports, 1960-1963 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Annual Reports, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Annual Reports, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Annual Reports, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Annual Reports, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Annual Reports, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Annual Reports, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - General
    - General, 1959-1975 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - College Decorator, 1963-1968 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Federal Funding, 1962-1967 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Handicapped Access, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Sanitation System, 1962-1971 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Trash Can Contest, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Ainsworth Gym, 1965-1975 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Botanic Garden-Annual Reports, 1960-1974 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Botanic Garden-General, 1960-1972 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Burton Hall, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Clark Science Center
    See also Series V. Admin. Offices-Development- Foundations-[Edna McConnell] Clark Foundation
    - General, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - General, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - General, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - General, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - General, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - General, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - General, 1967-1974 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Opening Ceremonies, 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - McConnell Hall Mural, 1964-1974 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Sabin and Reed Sculpture, 1965-1967 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - College Hall, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - College Hall-Carlile Carillon, 1963-1974 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Davis Student Center
    See Series XVII. Students-Student Centers-Davis Student Ctr.
  - Elm Street-Purchase of Methodist Church at 90 Elm St., 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Fine Arts Center, 1962-1967 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Fine Arts Center, JAN-JUN 1968 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Fine Arts Center, JUL-DEC 1968 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Fine Arts Center, 1969-1973 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Gateway House, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Green Street, 1967-1971 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Hatfield Hall, 1961-1975 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - John M. Green Hall, 1961; 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Josten Library
    See Series VII. Buildings & Grounds-Mendenhall Center for the Performing Arts-Josten Library
  - Juniper Lodge, 1960-1974 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Mendenhall Center for the Performing Arts
    - General, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - General, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - General, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - General, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - General, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - General, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - General, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - General, 1968-1970 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Bells, 1966-1975 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - April 1968 Deaths, 1968-1971 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Josten Library, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Morgan Hall, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Neilson Library, 1959-1960 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Neilson Library, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Neilson Library, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Paradise Pond, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Paradise Pond-Island Gazebo Hunt, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - President's House, 1960-1973 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Sage Hall, 1968-1972 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Scott Gym, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Seelye Hall, 1967; 1972-73 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Sophia Smith Homestead, 1967-1974 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Student Residences
    - General, 1962-1973 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Graduate Student Housing, 1966; 1972 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - House Plaques/Legends, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Baldwin House, 1968; 1973 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Chapin House, 1968; 1972 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Chase and Duckett Houses, 1966-1974 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Comstock House, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Cutter House, 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Dawes House, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Drew House, 1963-1970 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Franklin King House, 1968; 1975 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Gillett House, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Hampshire House, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Henshaw House
      See Series II. Academic Departments-Art-Ceramics Studio
    - Hopkins House, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Hubbard House, 1965; 1971 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Jordan House, 1964; 1969 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Lamont House, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Laura Scales House, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Martha Wilson House, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Morris House, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Morrow House, 1970; 1972 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Oak House, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Parsons House, 1972; undated (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Sessions House Annex, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Talbot House, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Tenney House, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Washburn House, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Ziskind House-Crew, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Wright Hall, 1959-1960 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Wright Hall, 1961-1963; 1974 (Box 6, Folder 38)
- Series VIII. COLLEGES AND UNIVERSITIES, 0.833 linear feet (2 containers)
  This series consists of correspondence, reports and news clippings from other institutions regarding cooperative programs, institutional activities and events, as well as common educational issues. The files are organized alphabetically by institution, with one file at the end of miscellaneous material, also filed alphabetically. There are a number of inauguration/ anniversary invitations and programs sent on a pro forma basis from other institutions everyyear. These are filed chronologically following the alphabetical institution files. For institutions of either the Five Colleges, Seven Sisters or Twelve College Exchange, see also Intercollegiate Associations.
  - Amherst College, 1959-1975 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Greenfield Community College, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Hampshire College, 1958-1964 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Hampshire College, 1965-1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Hampshire College-"More Power to Them..." (Planning Report), 1961 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Harvard University, 1960-1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Japan Women's University, 1962-64; 1973 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Mary Holmes Junior College
    See Series XIV. Intercollegiate Assoc-Five Colleges
  - Massachusetts, University of, 1959-1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1961; 1965 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Mount Holyoke College, 1959-1975 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Oxford University, 1960-1967 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Philippine Women's University, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Pierce College (Athens, Greece), 1962-1972 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Princeton University, 1964-1975 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Queens University (Ontario, Canada), 1970 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Radcliffe College, 1960-1963 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Robert College of Istanbul, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Simon's Rock, 1967-1971 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Vassar College, 1961-1975 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Wellesley College, 1960-1975 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Wesleyan University, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Wheaton College, 1966; 1972 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Williams College, 1962-1964 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Yale University, 1960-1971 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    see also Series XIII. Graduate Work-Master of Arts in Teaching
  - Miscellaneous, 1959-1975 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Inauguration/Anniversary Invitations & Programs, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Inauguration/Anniversary Invitations & Programs, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Inauguration/Anniversary Invitations & Programs, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Inauguration/Anniversary Invitations & Programs, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Series IX. COMMITTEES & BOARDS, 2.5 linear feet (6 containers)
  This series includes correspondence, reports and working papers of the standing and ad-hoc committees and boards of the college. The most central and far-reaching decision-making bodies are the Board of Trustees, the Board of Counselors, and the Committee on Planning and Resources (previously the College Planning Committee and the Faculty Planning Committee). However, college policy and the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act require the restriction of the records of both the Board of Trustees and the Board of Counselors. The records of the Committee on Planning and Resources contain the bulk of information on the debate over coeducation, as well as many budgetary and structural issues. More information about coeducation may be found in the folowing series:
  Series V. Administrative Offices-Development-Foundations-Clark Foundation (for a JAN 1969 coeducation proposal) Series VIII. Colleges & Universities-Yale University Series VIII. Colleges & Universities-Amherst College Series XIII. Graduate Work-School for Social Work-Male Students Series XIV. Intercollegiate Associations-Five Colleges-Amherst College-Coeducation Series XIV. Intercollegiate Associations-12-College Exchange
  Other significant committees in this series include several faculty committees, the Committee on Social Responsibility and the Committee on Student Affairs.